Finding Aid for the Oliver Cromwell Carmichael Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- The Series
  - Correspondence-Incoming
    - Ivey, John E., Jr. – Jack, Theodore (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Jackson, F. M. – James,Vernon (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Jamison, Henry D., Jr. – Jamison, Robert, Jr. (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Jenkins, Mrs. H. M. – Johnson, Dixon (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Johnson, Eldon L. (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Johnson, Elizabeth (Mrs. J. Fred) – Johnson, Walter F. (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Johnston, Eric – Jones, Devane (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Jones, D. Trotter – Jones, Weimar (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Jordan, B. Everett – Karpeles, Leo M. (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Karsten, Karl – Kelly, Thomas (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Kemp, Eva Deane – Kennerly, William J. (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Kent, M. O. – Keys, W.E. (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Khan, H. U. – Kilkenny, Kathy (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - King, C. G. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - King, C.L. – Kloetzel, Milton C. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Knapp, Bradford – Koefod, Paul E. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Koenig, E.F. – Lambert, Richard D. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Lambert, Richard D. – Lassiter, Robert, Jr. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Lathrop, Virginia Terrell – Leavitt, Sturgis E. (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Lee, C. Herbert – Lehman, Herbert H. (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Lehman, Katharine – Lesesne, J. M. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Leslie, Tom and Alta – Leyden, Louise (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Lichtenberger, The Rt. Rev. Arthur – Lipkin, Arthur Bennett (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Lipkin, Arthur Bennett – Liston, R.T. L. (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Litchfield, Edward H. – Lloyd, Evan B. (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Lloyd, R. McAllister – Logan, Sir Douglas (Jack) (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Logan, Sir Douglas (Jack) – Loveland, Mrs. James (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Lund, F.E. – Mackay, Colin B. (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Mackay, Colin B. – Mann, Howard G. (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Marin, Mrs. Fredrik – Martin, Thomas W. (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Martin, Thomas W. – Maxwell, Fred R. (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - May, Mrs. Geoffrey – McCargo, DeWitt (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - McCarley, J. Nathan, Jr. – McCoy, Kid (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - McCoy, Pressley C. – McCutcheon, Roger P. (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - McDavid, Mittie Owen – McGrath, Earl J. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - McGraw, Dr. R. P. – McKean, Hugh F. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - McKelden, Mayor Theodore R. – McLendon, L.P. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - McLester, James B. – McPheeters, T.S. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - McQueeny, S.J. – Merrill, Lilla Jones (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Merrill, Walter J. – Millis, John S. (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Mills, Frederick C. – Mitchell, Sidney A. (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Mitchell, W. H. – Montgomery, Walter S. (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Moon, Rexford G., Jr. – Moorer, Bessie (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Mordell, D.L. – Morgan, Elford C. (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Morgan, Hugh – Mortimer, Charles G. (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Morton, J.R. – Mott, George Fox (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Moudy, J. M. – Muller, Leo C. (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Mullins, David W. – Myres, J.N.L. (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Nabors, Alice M. – Newman, James B. (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Newman, J. H. – Nims, Harry D. (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Nisley, H.A. – Norton, E.B. (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Norton, Dr. J.W.R. – Ogburn, William F. (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Odgen, Frederic D. – Outler, Albert C. (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Owen, Charles D. – Palmer, W.B.(M.D.) (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Pannell, Anne – Pannell, Gary (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Pardee, Virginia (Mrs. Charles) – Partridge, R.G. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Partridge, Russell G. – Patterson, Sara C. (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Pattillo, Manning M. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Pattillo, Manning M. (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Patton, Francis L. – Peebles, Gertrude M. (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Peer, Ralph S. – Perry, John L. (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Peter, Lorraine – Phillips, Alma (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Phillips, Howard M. – Pierson, Harry H. (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Pierson, W.W. – Plank, J. Phillip (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Plemmons, W. H. (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Plimpton, Francis T.P. – Pomfret, John E. (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Ponder, Herbert M. – Poston, George R. (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Pow, Alex S. – Price, Don K. (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Price, Don K. – Proudley, Charles E. (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Provine, Robert Calhoun – Purcell, Clare (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Purks, Harris (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Purks, Harris – Quillian, William F., Jr. (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Quinn, E.C. – Randall, John A. (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Rees, Mayo – Reynolds, Charles H. (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Randall, William M. – Reed, Sarah R. (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Reynolds, Charles H. – Reynolds, W.B. (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Rhodes, Peyton N. – Richards, J. McDowell (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Richardson, E.S. – Robert, Joseph C. (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Roberts, Dayton Y. – Roberts, Eunice C. (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Roberts, John K. – Robertson, Reuben B. (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Robinson, Becky – Rogers, James F. (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Rogers, Louise – Rose, Frank (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Rose, Frank – Rosenhaupt, Hans (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Ross, Leticia – Rudd, Rogers (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Rude, Eric R. – Russell, Hudson (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Russell, John – Ryerson, Edward L. (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - St. George’s Society – Sanger, W. T. (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Sarcy, Hubert – Savage, Howard J. (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Saville, Mrs. Lillian – Schneider, Elsa (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Schnorrenberg, Laura (Mrs. Schaeffer) – Selden, Armistead (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Selden, William K. (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Self, Geddes – Shannon, Edgar R., Jr. (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Sharman, Jackson R. – Shelton, John L. (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Shepardson, Whitney – Simpson, William Henry Belk (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Sims, Cecil – Sipple, H.L., (June 1955) (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Sipple, H.L., (1955 – February 1956) (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Sipple, H.L., (Feb. 1956 – November 1958) (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Sipple, H.L., (1959–1961) (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Skipper, Margaret E. (Mrs. Howard E.) – Slocum, John H. (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Small, Patterson M. – Smith, Courtney (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Smith, Eppie Hayes (Mrs. Edward H.) – Smith, H. Alexander (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Smith, Hilton A. – Smith, Sydney (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Smits, Helen – Snyder, Lawrence (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Sockman, Ralph (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Soderquist, William G. – Spidle, Marion (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Spies, Tom D. – Spruill, J.A. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Spry, Walter – Stauss, Marjorie (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Stead, Lillian (Mrs. William) – Stephens, Peggy (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Sterling, J.E. Wallace – Stockton, Ralph M., Jr. (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Stoddard, George D. – Strickler, Karen (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Strode, Hudson – Sutton, Joseph L. (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Swalin, Benjamin F. – Toussig, Helen B. (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Taylor, Charles L. – Taylor, John W. (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Taylor, John W. – Taylor, Roy A. (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Tead, Ordway, (1957–1960) (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Tead, Ordway, (February 1960 – March 1962) (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Tead, Ordway, (1962–1965) (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Teagle, Raphiel – ten Hoor, M. (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Ten Hoor, Marten – ten Hoor, Marie (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Tenney, S. Marsh – Thomas, L.L> (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Thomason, Agnes Hardy (Mrs. W.D.) – Tickton, Sidney G. (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Tickson, Sidney G. – Totaro, Joseph V. (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Towle, Eleanor d. – Tribble, Harold W. (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Trigg, Florine H. – Tuck, Hallam (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Tucker, Hayse – Turbeville, H.B. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Turner, Edward L. (M.D.) – Vanderlip, Mrs. Frank (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Van Dusen, A. C. – Van Santvoord, George (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Van Wagenen, Richard W. – Vivion, Joseph King (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Vogel, Ralph H., (1954–1955) (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Vogel, Raph H., (1955–1956) (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Vogel, Ralph H., (1956–1961) (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Vogt, Ernest L. – Volker, J.F. (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Volker, J.F. (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Vowles, Guy R. – Warburg, Gerald F. (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Ward, Charles D. – Warren, W. Preston (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Wasson, A.W. – Watts, Bessie (Mrs. Thomas G.) (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Weaver, Fred – Wellemeyer, J.F. (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Wells, Franklin C. – Wescott, Roger (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Wessel, Nils Y. – Wheeler, Mrs. C.E. (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - White, Charles – Willham, Oliver S. (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Williams, Addison – Williams, Hubert (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Williams, J.D. – Williams, R. T. (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Williamson, Mrs. C. M. – Wilson, Joseph C. (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Wilson, Leonard R. – Wilson, Raymond G. (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Winfield, A. – Woodburne, L.S. (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Woodcock, Julian A. – Worley, Lillian (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Wormald, F.L. – Yeuell, Gladstone H. (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Yeder, Edwin M., Jr. – Young, Louise (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Young, Marcus – Zukowski, Charles F., Jr. (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Writings-Addresses
    - “The Business of Education” Montgomery, AL, February 5, 1927 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - “Tax Supported Colleges for Women in the U.S.” Asheville, NC, June 23, 1927 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - “The Home in the Citizenship Training” – P.T.A. October 1929; “Rhythm, Phrasing and Ensemble” – Alabama Music Teachers Association, March 1931 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - “The Alabama School Situation” (Radio talk), February 26, 1933 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - “Scholarship in American Education” Emory University, May 5, 1933 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - “What Will be the Outcome of the Public Works Administration Program?” (a Radio talk), February 11, 1934 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Baccalaureate Address. Alabama Polytechnic Institute, Auburn, May 29, 1934 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - “Radio Talk”, September 16, 1934 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - “Scholarship in American Education” Howard College, May 11, 1936 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - “Leadership and the Spirit of Learning” University of Alabama, May 24, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - “What is Education?” University of Chicago, April 15, 1938 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - “Some Assets of Progress” at Chamber of Commerce, Tulas, OK, January 9, 1940 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Address at Dinner for John D. Rockefeller at Vanderbilt University, May 2, 1941 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Address at Inauguration of President John E. Tomfret, College of William and Mary, Feburary 8, 1943 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - “Responsibility in Higher Education” at Union College, NY, May 11, 1946 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - “Change in Higher Education” Adelphi College, NY, June 1, 1946 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - “Some Problems and Trends” University of Pittsburgh, June 12, 1946 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - “Higher Education: the Next Fifty Years” Alabama College, October 14, 1946 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - “Industry and Education and Basic Research” Nutrition Foundation, November 14, 1946 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - “Effective Instruction” Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, Memphis, TN, December 12, 1946 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - “Education, Opportunities, and Perils” Cincinatti Schoolmaster Club, February 8, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - “Thomas Alva Edison, Inspirer of Man”, February 11, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - “Nursing and Nursing Education” Cornell University New York Hospital School of Nursing, April 16, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - “Education for Changing Times” National University Extension Association, Atlantic City, NJ, May 6, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Commencement address at Presbyterian Hospital School of Nursing, June 5, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Commencement address at Tulane University, Louisiana, June 11, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Commencement address at University of Chattanooga, TN, September 17, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - “ A Layman Replies” Fifth Avenue Presbyterian Church, NYC, October 19, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - “Maintaining High Quality in the Colleges” Meeting of the American Association of Colleges Cincinnati, OH, January 13, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - “Some Educational Frontiers” Founder’s Day Address, Collins College, February 21, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - “Regional Planning in Higher Education” University of Florida, March 4, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - “The Role of Higher Education in American Society” National Education Association Conference on Higher Education, Chicago, IL, March 22, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - “The Role of the Educated” Commencement Address at Stanford University, June 13, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - “Some Educational Frontiers” Brown University, June 19, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - “The Role of the Educated” Commencement address at the City College of New York, June 22, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - “Man’s Place and Hope” Inauguration of President Arthur S. Adams, University of New Hampshire, October 9, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - “Introduction of N. Baxter Jackson” at Newcomen Society, March 3, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Address to the Board of Trustees, State University of New York, April 4, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - “Scholarship – Yesterday and Today” Phi Beta Kappa Address Randolph-Macon Woman’s College, April 11, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - “Tomorrow’s Work” Vanderbilt University, June 5, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - “Tomorrow’s Work” University of Denver, June 11, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - “A Decade at Brooklyn College” Brooklyn College, NY, October 19, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - “This Country’s Role in the New World Order, Isolationism or World Leadership” Memphis, TN, November 21, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - “Bird’s – Eye View of Southern Progress” Southern Society, December 9, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 44)
    - “The Modern Imperative” LeHigh University, February 5, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 45)
    - “The Educational Enterprises” Honolulu, Hawaii, March 21, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 46)
    - “The University and the Changing Scene” Honolulu, Hawaii, March 24, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 47)
    - “Education-Its Problems and Prospects” Hilo, Hawaii, March 29, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 48)
    - “ Greetings to George F. Zook, President, American Council on Education” Annual Meeting of American Council on Education, May 5, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 49)
    - “The Educational Dilemma” University of Pittsburgh, May 9, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 50)
    - “The Outlook at Mid-Century” Bucknell University, June 11, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 51)
    - “The Frontiers of Peace” Pennsylvania State College, June 12, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 52)
    - “Contemporary Trends in the Arts College” Middlebury College, September 29, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 53)
    - “Higher Education: Some Problems and Prospects” Middle States Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, Atlantic City, NJ, November 24, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 54)
    - “The South at Mid Century” Wake Forest College, November 28, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 55)
    - “Problem Areas in Our Instructional Program” Conference of Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, Richmond Virginia, December 4, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 56)
    - “Leadership and Learning” Washington and Lee University, December 15, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 57)
    - “The University in 1950” University of Buffalo, January 5, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 58)
    - “Honoring Chancellor Harry W. Chase”, January 24, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 59)
    - “The Crisis in Higher Education” Furman University – April 20, 1951; with program (Box 23, Folder 60)
    - “America’s Problems and Prospects” Commencement address at University of Washington, June 9, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 61)
    - “Higher Education of Women: an Evaluation”, September 27, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 62)
    - “The University President” the inauguration of Philip G. Davidson as President of University of Louisville, October 30, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 63)
    - “Manpower Needs and their Implications for Education” New York, NY, November 2, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 64)
    - “Remarks by Oliver C. Carmichael” Fashion Institute, New York, NY, November 14, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 65)
    - “Science, Technology, and Progress” Annual Meeting of the Southern Research Institute, December 5, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 66)
    - “Higher Education – a Review” at the Southern University Conference, April 10, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 67)
    - “The Role of the Teacher” Alabama College, June 2, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 68)
    - “Recent Trends in Universities and Colleges in the U.S.A.” National Conference of Canadian Universities, Quebec, June 11, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 69)
    - “The University Today” Commencement at University of Michigan, June 14, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 70)
    - “Regional Associations: Background and Prospects” Memphis, TN, December 1, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 71)
    - “The Status of Liberal Education” Coker College, January 30, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 72)
  - Writings – Addresses
    - “Major Strengths and Weaknesses in American Higher Education” National Conference on Higher Education, Chicago, March 5, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - “State University (of New York) Five Year Review, March 20, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - “Some Critical Issues at Mid-Century” University of Texas, March 30, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - “Some Critical Issues at Mid-Century” St. Louis University, June 2, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - “Background of American Higher Education” Montreat, NC, June 23-26, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - “Critical Issues of Mid-Century” Montreat, NC, June 23-26, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - “How Planning for the Future is Going Forward in States and Regions” American Council on Education, October 6, 1955 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - “Some Comments on Medical Education” Meeting of Association of American Medical Colleges, 1957 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - “Redbrick and the Ivory Tower” Meeting of Association of Urban Universities, Detroit, November 4, 1957 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - “The Liberal Arts in Modern Society” Inauguration of O.C. Carmichael, Jr. as President of Converse College, SC, December 6, 1957 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - “Expanding Educational Opportunities” Asheville-Biltmore College, NC, February 5, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - “Leadership and Learning” Rollins College, Florida, February 3, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - “Can the Schools and Colleges Give What the Employer Wants?” Life Career Conference of Institute of Women’s Professional Relations, Birmingham, AL (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - “The Importance of Girls Going to College” radio interview, n.d (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - “Is Leisure a Curse or a Blessing?” Alabama Congress of Parents and Teachers, Decatur (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - “Greetings from the Association of Southern Colleges for Women” Montevallo, AL, n.d (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - “Alabama College Summer Program” radio address, n.d (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - “Marks of the Educated.” Baccalaureate address at Mississippi State College for Women, n.d (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - “Cultural Development in America” Address over Station WAPI on N.B.C. system, n.d (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - “Education and the New Deal” Southern Physical Education Association – n.d.; “The Challenge of the Churches in Higher Education” notice of a dedicatory address on, May 18, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Writings – Essays
    - “Adjusting the Curriculum to the Needs of Students” (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - “Alabama College Life”; “Significant Facts from Alabama Census 1930” (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - “Alabama College Summer Program” (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - “Backgrounds of American Higher Education (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - “Background of Higher Education in the British Colonies” (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - “Background of Higher Education in Ceylon” (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - “Background of Higher Education in Great Britain and Ireland” (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - “Background of Higher Education in the United States” (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - “Background of Higher Education in the United States (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - “Background of Higher Education – Pakistan” (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - “Background of Higher Education in South Africa” (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - “Beginnings of Educational Television in Alabama” (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - “Book reviews for John Gunther’s Inside Asia (New York, 1939) (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - “Cardinal Mercier’s Letter” (Box 24, Folder 34)
    - “College Teacher Preparation in Pennsylvania” (Box 24, Folder 35)
    - “Colleges for Women in America” (Box 24, Folder 36)
    - “The College for Women versus Coeducation” (Box 24, Folder 37)
    - “Colleges and Universities Faculty Needs” (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - “Colleges for Women – a Background” (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - “Compulsory Military Training in Peace – Time” (Box 24, Folder 40)
    - “The Crisis in Education” (New York Times, January 26, 1947) (Box 24, Folder 41)
    - “The Crisis in Humanistic Studies” (Box 24, Folder 42)
    - “A Critique of the College of Arts and Sciences” (Box 24, Folder 43)
    - “Diary of Visit to England, June 29 – July 20, 1953” (Box 24, Folder 44)
    - “Education and the New Deal” (Box 24, Folder 45)
  - Writings – Essays
    - “Educational Innovations” (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - “Experience in Belgium, December 12 – April 3” (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - “Foreword” (for Paul E.Koeford’s Academic Snakepit) (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - “Gandhism, an Interpretation” (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - “The Good Society by Walter Lippman” (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - “Graduate Education in the United States: the Nature of the Problem and the Elements in the Solution” (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - “Higher Education in Transition” (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - “Higher Education in the United States” (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - “Higher Education of Women” (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - “Highlights: Carnegie Foundation History” (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - “History of Education in Alabama” (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - “History of Women’s Colleges in America” (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - “How Planning for the Future is Going Forward in States and Regions” (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - “In Memoriam: Cason Jewell Callaway” (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - “Laws National and International Affecting Women” (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - “The Liberal Arts in Modern Society” (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - “Long-Range Prospects in American Higher Education” (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - “Memorandum on Academic Freedom” (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - “Memorandum on Higher Education” (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - “Music as a Social Force” (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - “Opening of Rhodes House”; “Oxford University and the Rhodes Scholarship” (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - “Our State College for Women” (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - “The Place of the Women’s College in Higher Education” (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - “Plan for Prohibition Enforcement” (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - “Progressive Education: the New Education versus the Old” (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - “Qualities Needed in a College President” (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - “The Rise of the General Education Movement” (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - “The Role of Significant Ideas in Higher Education” (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - “The Roots of Higher Education in Minnesota” (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - “Russia and ‘Life of Stalin’” (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - “Science, Technology, and Social Adjustment” (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - “Soft Pedagogy in the Colleges – a Rejoinder” (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - “The South and the Woman’s College” (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - “The Southern Colleges for Women” (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - “State-Supported Colleges for Women” (Box 25, Folder 35)